<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CovidInfo</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="A1">Corona viruses are a large family of viruses which may cause illness in animals or humans. In humans, several coronaviruses are known to cause respiratory infections ranging from the common cold to more severe diseases such as Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS) and Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome (SARS). The most recently discovered coronavirus causes coronavirus disease COVID-19.</string>
    <string name="message_one">Please note that information from\nthis chat will be used for\nmonitoring and management of the\ncurrent health crises and research\nin the fight against Covid-19</string>
    <string name="myth1">1. Spraying chlorine or alcohol on the skin kills viruses in the body</string>
    <string name="myth1a">Applying alcohol or chlorine to the body can cause harm, especially if it enters the eyes or mouth. Although people can use these chemicals to disinfect surfaces, they should not use them on the skin.\n\nThese products cannot kill viruses within the body.</string>
    <string name="myth2">2. Only older adults and young people are at risk</string>
    <string name="myth2a">SARS-CoV-2, like other coronaviruses, can infect people of any age. However, older adults and individuals with preexisting health conditions, such as diabetes or asthma, are more likely to become severely ill.</string>
    <string name="myth3">3. Children cannot get COVID-19</string>
    <string name="myth3a">All age groups can contract SARS-CoV-2.\n\nSo far, most cases have been in adults, but children are not immune. In fact, preliminary evidence suggests that children are just as likely to contract it, but their symptoms tend to be less severe.\n\nOn May 15, 2020, the WHO released a commentary about an inflammatory condition, affecting children and adolescents, that may have links with COVID-19.\n\nThe condition, called multisystem inflammatory condition, has features similar to Kawasaki disease and toxic shock syndrome.\n\nScientists currently know little about this condition, but research from May 2020 suggests that it is rare, “probably affecting no more than 1 in 1,000 children exposed to SARS-CoV-2.”</string>
    <string name="myth4">COVID-19 is just like the flu</string>
    <string name="myth4a">SARS-CoV-2 causes an illness that does have flu-like symptoms, such as aches, a fever, and a cough. Similarly, both COVID-19 and the flu can be mild, severe, or, in rare cases, fatal. Both can also lead to pneumonia.\n\nHowever, the overall profile of COVID-19 is more serious. Different countries have reported different mortality rates, and the case fatality rate in the U.S. appears to be around 6%.\n\nAlthough scientists are still working out the exact mortality rate, it is likely to be many times higher than that of seasonal flu.</string>
    <string name="myth5">5. Everyone with COVID-19 dies</string>
    <string name="myth5a">This statement is untrue. As we mentioned above, COVID-19 is only fatal for a small percentage of people.\n\nIn a recent report, the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention concluded that 80.9% of COVID-19 cases were mild.\n\nThe WHO also report that around 80% of people will experience a relatively mild form of the disease, which will not require specialist treatment in a hospital.\n\nMild symptoms may include a fever, a cough, a sore throat, tiredness, and shortness of breath.</string>
    <string name="myth6">6. There are currently no drugs licensed for the treatment or prevention of COVID-19</string>
    <string name="myth6a">While several drug trials are ongoing, there is currently no proof that hydroxychloroquine or any other drug can cure or prevent COVID-19. The misuse of hydroxychloroquine can cause serious side effects and illness and even lead to death. WHO is coordinating efforts to develop and evaluate medicines to treat COVID-19.</string>
    <string name="myth7">7. Adding pepper to your soup or other meals DOES NOT prevent or cure COVID-19</string>
    <string name="myth7a">Hot peppers in your food, though very tasty, cannot prevent or cure COVID-19. The best way to protect yourself against the new coronavirus is to keep at least 1 metre away from others and to wash your hands frequently and thoroughly. It is also beneficial for your general health to maintain a balanced diet, stay well hydrated, exercise regularly and sleep well.</string>
    <string name="myth8">8. COVID-19 IS NOT transmitted through houseflies</string>
    <string name="myth8a">To date, there is no evidence or information to suggest that the COVID-19 virus transmitted through houseflies. The virus that cause COVID-19 spreads primarily through droplets generated when an infected person coughs, sneezes or speaks. You can also become infected by touching a contaminated surface and then touching your eyes, nose or mouth before washing your hands. To protect yourself, keep at least 1-metre distance from others and disinfect frequently-touched surfaces. Clean your hands thoroughly and often and avoid touching your eyes, mouth and nose.</string>
    <string name="myth9">9. Spraying and introducing bleach or another disinfectant into your body WILL NOT protect you against COVID-19 and can be dangerous</string>
    <string name="myth9a">Do not under any circumstance spray or introduce bleach or any other disinfectant into your body. These substances can be poisonous if ingested and cause irritation and damage to your skin and eyes.\n\nBleach and disinfectant should be used carefully to disinfect surfaces only. Remember to keep chlorine (bleach) and other disinfectants out of reach of children.</string>
    <string name="myth10">10. Drinking methanol, ethanol or bleach DOES NOT prevent or cure COVID-19 and can be extremely dangerous</string>
    <string name="myth10a">Methanol, ethanol, and bleach are poisons. Drinking them can lead to disability and death. Methanol, ethanol, and bleach are sometimes used in cleaning products to kill the virus on surfaces – however you should never drink them. They will not kill the virus in your body and they will harm your internal organs.\n\nTo protect yourself against COVID-19, disinfect objects and surfaces, especially the ones you touch regularly. You can use diluted bleach or alcohol for that. Make sure you clean your hands frequently and thoroughly and avoid touching your eyes, mouth and nose.</string>
    <string name="myth11">11. 5G mobile networks DO NOT spread COVID-19</string>
    <string name="myth11a">Viruses cannot travel on radio waves/mobile networks. COVID-19 is spreading in many countries that do not have 5G mobile networks.\n\nCOVID-19 is spread through respiratory droplets when an infected person coughs, sneezes or speaks. People can also be infected by touching a contaminated surface and then their eyes, mouth or nose.</string>
    <string name="myth12">12. Exposing yourself to the sun or to temperatures higher than 25C degrees DOES NOT prevent the coronavirus disease (COVID-19)</string>
    <string name="myth12a">You can catch COVID-19, no matter how sunny or hot the weather is. Countries with hot weather have reported cases of COVID-19. To protect yourself, make sure you clean your hands frequently and thoroughly and avoid touching your eyes, mouth, and nose.</string>
    <string name="myth13">13. You can recover from the coronavirus disease (COVID-19). Catching the new coronavirus DOES NOT mean you will have it for life.</string>
    <string name="myth13a">Most of the people who catch COVID-19 can recover and eliminate the virus from their bodies. If you catch the disease, make sure you treat your symptoms. If you have cough, fever, and difficulty breathing, seek medical care early – but call your health facility by telephone first. Most patients recover thanks to supportive care.</string>
    <string name="myth14">14. Drinking alcohol does not protect you against COVID-19 and can be dangerous</string>
    <string name="myth14a">Frequent or excessive alcohol consumption can increase your risk of health problems.</string>
    <string name="myth15">15. COVID-19 virus can be transmitted in areas with hot and humid climates</string>
    <string name="myth15a">The best way to protect yourself against COVID-19 is by maintaining physical distance of at least 1 metre from others and frequently cleaning your hands. By doing this you eliminate viruses that may be on your hands and avoid infection that could occur by then touching your eyes, mouth, and nose.</string>
    <string name="q1">1. What is the novel coronavirus?</string>
    <string name="a1">This is a new strain of coronavirus that has not been previously identified in humans.\nCoronaviruses are a large family of viruses that are known to cause illness in humans and animals. In humans, this large family of viruses are known to cause illness ranging from the common cold to Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome (SARS).</string>
    <string name="q2">2. What are the symptoms of novel coronavirus?</string>
    <string name="a2">In confirmed cases of illness in humans, common symptoms have been acute, serious respiratory illness with fever, cough, shortness of breath, and breathing difficulties. Based on current clinical experience, the infection generally presents as pneumonia. It has caused kidney failure and death in some cases. It is important to note that the current understanding of the illness caused by this infection is based on a limited number of cases and may change as more information becomes available.</string>
    <string name="q3">3. Can it be transmitted from person to person?</string>
    <string name="a3">This is not known with certainty at this time. The cases occurring in the same family raises the possibility of limited human-to-human transmission. Alternatively, it is possible that the infected family members were exposed to the same source of infection, for example, in a household or workplace.</string>
    <string name="q4">4. How could I become infected with this virus?</string>
    <string name="a4">To date, we do not know how humans have become infected with this virus. Investigations are underway to determine the virus source, types of exposure that lead to infection, mode of transmission and the clinical pattern and course of disease.</string>
    <string name="q5">5. Is there a vaccine for the novel coronavirus?</string>
    <string name="a5">There is no vaccine currently available.</string>
    <string name="q6">6. Is there a treatment for the novel coronavirus?</string>
    <string name="a6">There is no specific treatment for disease caused by novel coronavirus. However, many of the symptoms caused by this virus can be treated and therefore treatment should be based on the symptoms of the patient. Moreover, supportive care for infected persons can be highly effective.</string>
    <string name="q7">7. What can I do to protect myself?</string>
    <string name="a7">Exactly how people become infected with this virus is not known at this time. However, some general measures that would be prudent and help prevent the acquisition of any respiratory illness are to avoid close contact, when possible, with anyone who shows symptoms of illness (coughing and sneezing), and to maintain good hand hygiene.</string>
    <string name="q8">8. How many people have been infected by the novel coronavirus?</string>
    <string name="a8">WHO is closely monitoring the situation and regularly publishes information about the disease. For more go to http://www.who.int/csr/disease/coronavirus_infections/en/</string>
    <string name="q9">9. How widespread is the novel coronavirus?</string>
    <string name="a9">It is unknown how widespread this virus may be.\nWHO is encouraging Member States to continue to closely monitor for severe acute respiratory infections (SARI) and to carefully review any unusual patterns of SARI or pneumonia. WHO will continue to share information as it is made available.</string>
    <string name="q10">10. Are health workers at risk from the novel coronavirus?</string>
    <string name="a10">Health care workers come into contact with patients with many different infectious illnesses more often than the general public. Therefore WHO recommends that health care workers consistently apply appropriate infection prevention and control measures.</string>
    <string name="q11">11. Is the novel coronavirus like SARS?</string>
    <string name="a11">SARS is a coronavirus that was identified in 2003 and belongs to the same large family of viruses as the novel coronavirus. Therefore, SARS and the novel coronavirus are distantly related. Both viruses are capable of causing severe disease. However, they have important differences based on current information. Most importantly, the novel coronavirus does not appear to transmit easily between people while the SARS virus was much more transmissible.</string>
    <string name="q12">12. Is it true that this novel coronavirus originated from bats?</string>
    <string name="a12">This is one possibility but the origin of the virus has not yet been established.</string>
    <string name="q13">13. Can humans become infected with novel coronavirus from animals? If so, which ones should we be concerned about?</string>
    <string name="a13">WHO is closely monitoring the situation to identify how people are being exposed. There is currently no direct evidence that the human cases were exposed through direct contact with animals.</string>
    <string name="q14">14. What is WHO recommending countries do?</string>
    <string name="a14">WHO encourages all Member States to enhance their surveillance for severe acute respiratory infections (SARI) and to carefully review any unusual patterns of SARI or pneumonia cases.\nWHO urges Member States to notify or verify to WHO any suspected or confirmed case of infection with novel coronavirus.</string>
    <string name="q15">15. Has WHO recommended any travel or trade restrictions related to this new virus?</string>
    <string name="a15">No. WHO does not recommend any travel or trade restrictions with respect to this event. WHO will continue to provide updated information as it is available.</string>
</resources>
